My name is Katrina Spade, and I grew up in a medical family
اسمي كاترينا سبايد، ولقد ترعرعت في عائلة أغلب أفرادها من الأطباء
where it was fairly normal to talk about death and dying at the dinner table.
حيث كان التحدث عن الموت على طاولة الغداء أمراً عادياً للغاية.
But I didn't go into medicine like so many of my family members.
إلّا أنني لم أتوجه لامتهان الطب كالعديد من أفراد أسرتي.
Instead, I went to architecture school to learn how to design.
بل ذهبت إلى معهد الهندسة المعمارية لكي أتعلّم التّصميم.
And while I was there, I began to be curious
وبتواجدي هناك، انتابني الفضول
about what would happen to my physical body after I died.
حول مصير جسدي بعد الموت.
What would my nearest and dearest do with me?
ما الذي سيفعله أقاربي وأحبتي به؟
So if the existence and the fact of your own mortality
فإذا لم يكن الوجود وحقيقة فنائنا مصدر إحباطٍ لكم،
the state of our current funerary practices will.
فإنَّ حالنا الراهن فيما يخص ممارسات الجنائز كفيل بذلك.
Today, almost 50 percent of Americans choose conventional burial.
اليوم حوالي خمسين بالمئة من الأمريكيين يلجؤون لمراسم الدفن التقليدية في المقابر.
Conventional burial begins with embalming,
أولى المراحل هي التحنيط،
where funeral staff drain bodily fluid
حيث يخرج العاملون في دار الجنائز السوائل من جسد الميت،
and replace it with a mixture designed to preserve the corpse
ويستبدلونها بخليط مصمَّم للمحافظة على الجثّة
and give it a lifelike glow.
وإعطائها منظرًا نابضًا بالحياة.
Then, as you know, bodies are buried in a casket
ثم توضع الجثّة في تابوت كما تعلمون جميعكم
in a concrete-lined grave
ليتم دفنها في قبر مبطّن بالإسمنت
in a cemetery.
داخل المقبرة.
All told, in US cemeteries,
بالمجمل، نحن نقوم في الولايات المتحدة
we bury enough metal to build a Golden Gate Bridge,
بدفن الحديد بكميّات كافية لبناء جسر بوابة ذهبية آخر،
enough wood to build 1,800 single family homes,
ومن الخشب ما يعادل بناء 1800 منزل عائلي،
and enough formaldehyde-laden embalming fluid
ومن سائل (الفورمالديهايد لادن) المستخدم في التحنيط
to fill eight Olympic-size swimming pools.
ما يكفي لملئ ثمانية مسابح أولمبية.
In addition, cemeteries all over the world are reaching capacity.
وفي المقابل، العديد من المقابر في أنحاء العالم
Turns out, it doesn't really make good business sense
اتضح أنّ بيع قطعة أرض لشخص ما بصورة دائمة يتنافى مع المفاهيم التجاريّة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Whose idea was that?
كانت فكرة من هذه؟
In some places, you can't buy a plot no matter how much money you have.
في بعض المناطق لا يمكنك شراء قطعة أرض مهما بلغت كمية النّقود بحوزتك.
As a result, cremation rates have risen fast.
نتيجة لذلك، ارتفعت تكاليف عمليّات حرق الجثث بسرعة.
In 1950, if you suggested your grandmother be incinerated after she died,
في عام 1950، لو اقترحت على جدّتك حرق جثّتها بعد موتها،
you'd probably be kicked from the family deathbed.
لطردوك على الأرجح بعيداً.
But today, almost half of Americans choose cremation,
لكن اليوم، نصف الأمريكيين تقريبًا يختارون عملية إحراق الجثث،
citing simpler,
محتجّين بكونها أبسط،
cheaper
أرخص
and more ecological as reasons.
وصديقة للبيئة.
I used to think that cremation was a sustainable form of disposition,
كنت أعتقد أنَّ حرق الجثث شكل مستدام لانتقال الملكية،
but just think about it for a second.
لكن فكّروا في الأمر للحظة.
Cremation destroys the potential we have
حرق الجثث يحرمنا من القدرة
to give back to the earth after we've died.
على العطاء للأرض بعد موتنا.
It uses an energy-intensive process to turn bodies into ash,
فتحويل الجثة إلى رماد يستهلك كميّة هائلة من الطاقة،
polluting the air and contributing to climate change.
إضافة إلى تلويث البيئة والمساهمة في التغير المناخي.
All told, cremations in the US
إجمالا، حرق الجثث في الولايات المتحدة
emit a staggering 600 million pounds of carbon dioxide
يتسبّب بانبعاث 600 مليون رَطْل سنويًا من غاز ثنائي أكسيد الكربون
into the atmosphere annually.
في الغلاف الجوي.
The truly awful truth
الحقيقة المروّعة
is that the very last thing that most of us will do on this earth
هي أنّ آخر ما سوف يقوم به معظمنا على كوكب الأرض
is poison it.
هو تسميمه.
It's like we've created, accepted and death-denied our way into a status quo
كأنّنا أنشأنا وتقبّلنا مسلكنا نحو وضع راهن يفرّقنا عن
that puts as much distance between ourselves and nature
الطبيعة بأكبر قدر إنساني ممكن، وقمنا بإنكار حدوثه.
Our modern funerary practices are designed to stave off
إنّ العادات الجنائزيّة الجديدة مصمَّمة لدرء العمليّة
the natural processes that happen to a body after death.
الطبيعية التي تحدث في أجسادنا بعد الموت
In other words, they're meant to prevent us from decomposing.
بعبارة أخرى، هي تمنع جثثنا من التحلّل.
But the truth
لكنّ الحقيقة
is that nature is really, really good at death.
هي أنّ الطبيعة جيّدة، جيّدة جدًا في الموت.
We've all seen it.
كلّنا رأينا ذلك.
When organic material dies in nature,
عندما تموت المادة العضوية في الطبيعة،
microbes and bacteria break it down into nutrient-rich soil,
تقوم البكتيريا والميكروبات بتبسيطها إلى تربة غنيّة بالمغذيات،
completing the life cycle.
مكملة بذلك دورة الحياة.
In nature, death creates life.
في الطبيعة، الموت يخلق الحياة.
Back in architecture school, I was thinking about all this,
عندما كنت في معهد الهندسة المعمارية، فكّرت في كلّ هذا،
and I set out on a plan to redesign death care.
وقمت بوضع مخطط من أجل إعادة تصميم مراحل رعاية الموتى.
Could I create a system
هل كان في مقدوري أن أبدع نظامًا
that was beneficial to the earth
يكون مفيدًا للأرض
and that used nature as a guide rather than something to be feared?
ويستنجد بالطبيعة كدليل بدل الاعتماد على شيء تُخْشى عواقبه؟
Something that was gentle to the planet?
وأن يكون لطيفًا على الكوكب؟
That planet, after all, supports our living bodies
ذلك الكوكب الذي حمل أجسادنا الحيّة، بعد كل شيء
our whole lives.
طيلة حياتنا.
And while I was mulling this all over
وبينما كنت أدرس في كلّ هذا
over the drawing board,
على لوحة الرسم،
the phone rang.
رنّ الهاتف.
It was my friend Kate.
لقد كانت صديقتي كيت.
She was like, "Hey, have you heard about the farmers
كانت تقول: "مرحبًا، هل سمعت بالمزارعين
who are composting whole cows?"
الذين يصنعون السماد من أبقار بأكملها؟
And I was like, "Mmmm."
وأجبت: "امممم".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Turns out that farmers in agricultural institutions
اتّضح أنّ المزارعين في المؤسسات الزراعية
have been practicing something called livestock mortality composting
كانوا يمارسون ما يسمّى التّسميد بالماشية النافقة
for decades.
لعقود.
Mortality composting is where you take an animal high in nitrogen
هذا النوع من التسميد هو عندما تأخذ الحيوان الغني بالنتروجين
and cover it with co-composting materials that are high in carbon.
لتغمره بمواد تساعد في التسميد والتّي تكون غنية بالكربون.
It's an aerobic process, so it requires oxygen,
هي عملية هوائية، فهي تحتاج الأكسجين،
and it requires plenty of moisture as well.
كما أنّها تتطلب الكثير من الرطوبة كذلك.
In the most basic setup, a cow is covered with a few feet of wood chips,
في أبسط الإعدادات، تتمّ تغطية البقرة ببضعة أقدام من رقائق الخشب،
which are high in carbon,
التّي هي غنية بالكربون،
and left outside for nature, for breezes to provide oxygen
لتترك في الخارج للطبيعة، للنّسائم لتزوّدها بالأكسجين
and rain to provide moisture.
وللمطر لتوفير الرطوبة.
In about nine months,
وفي حوالي تسعة أشهر،
all that remains is a nutrient-rich compost.
كلّ ما يتبقى هو سماد غنيٌ بالمغذّيات.
The flesh has been decomposed entirely,
تحلّل اللحم بالكامل،
as have the bones.
وكذا العظام.
I know.
أعرف.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So I would definitely call myself a decomposition nerd,
لذا بإمكاني تسمية نفسي بمهووسة التحلل
but I am far, far from a scientist,
لكنني بعيدة، عن كوني عالمة.
and one way you can tell this is true
هنالك طريقة واحدة لتصديق الأمر
is that I have often called the process of composting "magic."
وهي أنّني غالبًا ما اُطلق على عملية التحلل "سحر".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So basically, all we humans need to do
أساسًا، كل ما علينا نحن البشر أن نفعله
is create the right environment for nature to do its job.
هو أن نوفّر للطبيعة البيئة المناسبة لتقوم بعملها
It's like the opposite of antibacterial soap.
إنّها كنقيض الصابون المضاد للجراثيم
Instead of fighting them,
فبدل القضاء عليها،
we welcome microbes and bacteria in with open arms.
نرحّب بالميكروبات والبكتيريا بحفاوة
These tiny, amazing creatures
تللك الكائنات الضئيلة المدهشة
break down molecules into smaller molecules and atoms,
تفكّك الجزيئات إلى ذرات وجزيئات أصغر،
which are then incorporated into new molecules.
تدخل فيما بعد في تركيب جزيئات جديدة.
In other words, that cow is transformed.
بعبارة أخرى، تلك البقرة تحوّلت.
It's no longer a cow.
لم تعد بقرة.
It's been cycled back into nature.
تمّت إعادة تدويرها في الطبيعة.
See? Magic.
أرأيتم؟ سحر.
You can probably imagine the light bulb that went off in my head
بإمكانكم ربّما تصوّر الفكرة التّي راودت ذهني
after I received that phone call.
بعد تلقي تلك المكالمة.
I began designing a system
بدأت بتصميم نظام
based on the principles of livestock mortality composting
مرتكز على مبادئ التسميد بالماشية النافقة
that would take human beings and transform them into soil.
والذي يأخذ الكائنات البشرية ويحوّلها إلى تربة.
Fast-forward five years
وفي غضون خمس سنوات
and the project has grown in ways I truly never could have imagined.
نمى المشروع بطرق لم أكن صدقًا لأتخيّلها.
We've created a scalable, replicable non-profit urban model
قمنا بخلق نموذج مدني، قابل للتطوير، وإعادة التطبيق، بهدف غير ربحي.
based on the science of livestock mortality composting
مرتكز على علم التسميد بالماشية النافقة
that turns human beings into soil.
الذي يحوّل الكائنات البشرية إلى تربة.
We've partnered and collaborated with experts in soil science,
قمنا بالشراكة والتعاون مع خبراء في علم التربة،
decomposition, alternative death care,
التحلّل، رعاية الموتى البديلة،
law and architecture.
القانون، والهندسة المعمارية.
We've raised funds from foundations and individuals
جمعنا الأموال من مؤسساتٍ وأفراد
in order to design a prototype of this system,
من أجل تصميم نموذج مبدئي لهذا النظام،
and we've heard from tens of thousands of people all over the world
وكنا قد تلقينا رغبات عشرات الآلاف من الأشخاص حول العالم
who want this option to be available.
في أن يكون هذا الخيار متاحًا
OK.
حسنًا.
In the next few years,
في السنوات القليلة القادمة،
it's our goal to build the first full-scale human composting facility
سيكون هدفنا بناء أول منشأة شاملة للتسميد بواسطة الإنسان
right in the city of Seattle.
تمامًا في مدينة سياتل.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Imagine it,
تخيلوا الأمر،
part public park,
حديقة عامة من جهة،
part funeral home,
موقع للدفن من جهة أخرى،
part memorial to the people we love,
ونصب تذكاري للأشخاص الذين نحبهم،
a place where we can reconnect with the cycles of nature
مكان نستطيع فيه إعادة الإتصال مع دورات الطبيعة
and treat bodies with gentleness and respect.
ونعامل فيه أجسادنا بلطف واحترام.
The infrastructure is simple.
البنية الأساسيّة بسيطة.
Inside a vertical core,
داخل جوف عمودي،
bodies and wood chips undergo accelerated natural decomposition,
تخضع الجثث ورقائق الخشب للتحلّل بشكل طبيعي معجّل،
or composting,
أو التحول إلى سماد،
and are transformed into soil.
لتصبح فيما بعد تربة.
When someone dies, their body is taken to a human composting facility.
عندما يموت شخص ما، تؤخذ جثته إلى منشأة تسميد بشرية.
After wrapping the deceased in a simple shroud,
وبعد تغطية الميّت بكفن بسيط،
friends and family carry the body to the top of the core,
يحمل الأصدقاء والأقارب الجثة ويضعونها فوق الفجوة،
which contains the natural decomposition system.
التي تحوي نظام التحلّل الطبيعي.
During a laying in ceremony,
خلال ترتيب المراسم،
they gently place the body into the core
يقومون بوضع الجثة بلطف في قلب تلك الفجوة
and cover it with wood chips.
ويغطونها برقائق الخشب.
This begins the gentle transformation from human to soil.
هنا تبدأ أولى مراحل التحوّل اللطيف من إنسان إلى تربة.
Over the next few weeks, the body decomposes naturally.
وفي الأسابيع القليلة الموالية، تتحلل الجثث بشكل طبيعي.
Microbes and bacteria break down carbon, then protein,
تفكّك الميكروبات والبكتيريا الكربون، ثم البروتين
to create a new substance,
لتخلق مادة جديدة،
a rich, earthy soil.
وسطًا ترابيًا غنيًا.
This soil can then be used to grow new life.
بالإمكان إستغلال هذه التربة في تنمية حياة جديدة.
Eventually, you could be a lemon tree.
في النهاية، يمكنك أن تصبح شجرة ليمون.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Yeah, thank you.
نعم، شكرًا لكم.
Who's thinking about lemon meringue pie right now?
من منكم يفكّر في فطيرة مارينج الليمون الآن؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
A lemon drop?
قطرة ليمون؟
Something stronger?
شيء أقوى؟
So in addition to housing the core,
بالإضافة إلى احتوائها لتلك الفجوات
these buildings will function to support the grieving
فإنّ المباني ستكتسب أجواء ملائمة للتحسّر والحداد
by providing space for memorial services and end-of-life planning.
من خلال توفير مساحات خاصّة بالخدمات التذكارية والتخطيط لما بعد الموت.
The potential for repurposing is huge.
بالإمكان تطويعها لأغراض أخرى.
Old churches and industrial warehouses can be converted into places
يمكن أن تحوّل الكنائس القديمة والمستودعات الصناعية إلى أماكن
where we create soil and honor life.
ننشأ فيها التربة ونشرّف الحياة.
We want to bring back the aspect of ritual
نريد إعادة بعث مفهوم الطقوس
that's been diluted over the past hundred years
التي تمّ طمسها على مدى مئات السنين الماضية
as cremation rates have risen
بارتفاع تكاليف الحرق
and religious affiliation has declined.
ونقص الوازع الديني.
Our Seattle facility will function as a model for these places
منشأتنا في سياتل ستكون بمثابة نموذج لهذه الأمكنة
all over the world.
في جميع أنحاء العالم.
We've heard from communities in South Africa, Australia,
لقد أخذنا بعدّة مجتمعات في جنوب إفريقيا، أستراليا،
the UK, Canada and beyond.
المملكة المتحدة، كندا وغيرها.
We're creating a design toolkit
نحن نقوم بإنشاء أدوات تصميم
that will help others design and build facilities
تساعد الآخرين على تصميم وبناء منشآت
that will contain technical specifications
تحوي مواصفات فنية
and regulatory best practices.
وأفضل الممارسات التنظيمية.
We want to help individuals, organizations,
نريد مساعدة الأفراد، المؤسسات،
and down the road, municipalities
ومن في طريقهم، على إبداع تصاميم
design and build facilities in their own cities.
وبناء منشآت في مدنهم الخاصة.
The idea is that every one of these places should look and feel completely different
الفكرة تكمن في أنّه ينبغي على هذه الأماكن أن تكون متباينة شكلًا وإحساسًا
with the same system inside.
مع احتواء نفس النظام.
They're really meant to be designed for the neighborhood in which they reside
قصد فعلًا بها أن تكون مصممة خصيصًا للحيّ الذي سكنوا فيه
and the community which they serve.
والمجتمع الذي خدموه.
The other idea is for supportive staff to be on hand
الفكرة الأخرى هي أن يكون طاقم الدعم
to help families with the care and preparation of loved ones' bodies.
تحت إمرة العائلات لمساعدتهم في رعاية وتجهيز جثث أحبّائهم.
We're banishing practices that bewilder and disempower
إنّنا نحظر السلوكات التعجيزية والمثيرة للإحراج
and creating a system that is beautiful and meaningful
ونخلق نظامًا جميلًا وهادفًا
and transparent.
وصريحًا.
We believe that access to ecological death care
نحن نؤمن بأنّ الدخول إلى دار رعاية موتى بيئيّة
is a human right.
حق إنساني.
OK, so you know the old saying,
حسنًا، أنتم تعرفون المقولة القديمة،
if you can compost a cow, you can compost a human?
إذا حولت بقرة إلى سماد، فيمكنك فعل المثل بالإنسان؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Turns out, it's true.
اتّضح أنّها صحيحة.
Since 2014, we've been running a pilot project
منذ عام 2014، ونحن ندير مشاريع تجريبية
in the hills of North Carolina
في تلال نورث كارولينا
with the Forensic Anthropology Department at Western Carolina University.
بالشراكة مع قسم الأنثروبولوجيا الشرعية بجامعة كارولينا الغربية.
Six donor bodies have been covered in wood chips,
تمّت تغطية ستّة جثث من المتبرعين برقائق الخشب،
oxygen provided by breezes,
الأكسجين متوافر من خلال النّسيم،
microbes and bacteria doing their jobs.
وتقوم الميكروبات والبكتيريا بواجبها.
This pilot program has allowed us to demonstrate that it's possible
سمح لنا هذا المشروع التجريبي بإثبات إمكانية
to harness the incredible power of natural decomposition
تسخير قوة التحلل الطبيعي المذهلة
to turn human bodies into soil,
في جعل الجثث البشرية تربة،
and we're working with other universities as well.
كما أنّنا نعمل مع جامعات أخرى كذلك.
Soil scientists at Washington State University,
علماء التربة في جامعة ولاية واشنطن،
the grad students, anyway,
أو طلاب التخرّج، على أي حال،
are working to compost teeth with amalgam fillings
يعملون على تحويل الأسنان إلى سماد مع إضافة مزيج مخلوط بالزئبق
so that we can understand what happens to the mercury therein.
حتّى نرى ما يحدث له.
Next up, we'll be beginning experiments
الخطوة التالية هي مباشرة تجارب
to determine what happens to chemo drugs and pharmaceuticals
لتحديد ما يطرأ على العقاقير والمواد الصيدلانية
during the composting process,
خلال عملية التسميد،
and whether additional remediation will be needed.
وفيما إذا يتطلب الأمر معالجات إضافية.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
composting creates a great deal of heat,
عمليّات التسميد تصدر كميات عالية من الحرارة،
especially this particular type of composting.
وخاصّة هذا النوع من التسميد.
One week after we began composting our fifth donor body,
في الأسبوع الأول من تسميدنا للجثة الخامسة من المتبرعين
the temperature inside that mound of wood chips
بلغت درجة الحرارة داخل كومة رقائق الخشب
reached 158 degrees Fahrenheit.
158 درجة فهرنهايت.
Imagine harnessing that heat to create energy
تخيلوا استغلال تلك الحرارة لإنتاج الطاقة
or comfort the grieving on a cold day.
أو مواساة أجواء الحداد في يوم بارد.
The death care revolution has begun.
لقد بدأت الثورة في رعاية الموتى.
It's an exciting time to be alive.
إنّه وقت مثير لتكون فيه على قيد الحياة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)